Bedau, Hugo A.; Papers apap199
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Scholarship and Teaching, 1958-2002; 1; 6 cubic ft.
  - Studies/Proposals/Reports, 1958-1999; 1.4
    This subseries contains drafts of academic papers, grant proposals and reports. This subseries also features Bedau and Michael Radelet's Miscarriages of Justice in Potentially Capital Cases. This section includes: drafts, professional critiques, testimonies, correspondence, notes, and news clippings.
    - Arbitrary Death Sentencing Research Project, 1972 (Box 2 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 50)
    - "Capital Punishment in New Jersey: Documents and Studies" edited by Hugo Bedau, 1958 (Box 2 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 51)
    - "Deterrence and the Death Penalty", 1971 (Box 2 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 52)
    - "Discretionary Sentencing and severity of Sanction". Research Proposal by Hugo Bedau, Bill Bowers, and John Flackett, 1974 (Box 2 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 53)
    - "The Future of the Death Penalty the Need for a National Project in Social Science Research on Capital Punishment", 1973 (Box 2 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 54)
    - "The Future of Capital Punishment -- A Problem for Law and Social Science", 1973 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 1)
    - "Legislative Report: Should New Jersey Abolish Capital Punishment" WNTA Ch. 13 ABC Network, New Jersey, 1958 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 2)
    - "An Inventory of Death Penalty Research Projects". Supplementary Report, 1973 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 3)
    - Proposals to Foundations, 1973 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 4)
    - "Social Science Research and the Death Penalty in America: An Interim Report". By Hugo Bedau and Elliott Currie, 1973 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 5)
    - "Social Science Research and the Death Penalty in America: An Interim Report". By Hugo Bedau and Elliott Currie, 1973 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 6)
    - "A Study of Murder and Capital Punishment in the United States", 1961 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 7)
    - "Worldwide Abolition of Capital Punishment, with special reference to Great Britain and Canada, 1965-1970", 1971 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 8)
    - Miscarriages of Justice in Potentially Capital Cases. Hugo Bedau/Michael Radelet Study -- Notes, 1985 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 9)
    - Miscarriages of Justice, Correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 10)
    - Miscarriages of Justice, Response to Bedau-Radelet Death Penalty Study. Report to U.S. Attorney General by Stephan J. Markman, 1986 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 11)
    - Miscarriages of Justice, "Protecting the Innocent: A Response to the Bedau/Radelet Study". Stanford Law Review. By Stephen Markman and Paul Cassell, 1988 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 12)
    - Miscarriages of Justice, "The Myth of Infallibility: A Reply to Markman and Cassell". Stanford Law Review, 1988 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 13-14)
    - Miscarriages of Justice, Other Versions of Bedau/Radelet Study, 1985-1988 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 15)
    - Miscarriages of Justice, Media Response to Bedau/Radelet Study, 1985-1993 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 16-17)
    - Miscarriages of Justice, 1993 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 18)
      Testimony before House and Senate Judiciary committees by Paul Cassell, April, July 1993. Testimony before US Senate by Hugo Bedau, Aug. 1993.
    - Miscarriages of Justice, "Erroneous Convictions in Capital Cases". By Michael Radelet and Hugo Bedau, 1995 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 19)
    - Miscarriages of Justice, "Erroneous Convictions in Capital Cases". By Michael Radelet and Hugo Bedau, 1999 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 20)
  - Book Chapters, 1979-2003; Undated; 1.5
    This subseries contains drafts of chapters on capital punishment that Bedau contributed to various books.
    - "Abolishing the Death Penalty Even for the Worst Murderers", 1999 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 21)
    - "Abolishing the Death Penalty in the United States: An Analysis of Institutional Obstacles and Future Prospects". Chapter in Capital Punishment by Peter Hodgkinson, 2003 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 22)
    - "Capital Punishment". Chapter in Matters of Life and Death, edited by Tom Regan, 1980 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 23)
    - "Capital Punishment". Chapter in Matters of Life and Death 2nd edition, edited by Tom Regan, 1985 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 24)
    - "Capital Punishment". Chapter in Matters of Life and Death 3rd edition, edited by Tom Regan, 1992 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 25)
    - "Capital Punishment". Chapter in The Oxford Handbook of Practical Ethics, edited by Hugh La Follette, 2003 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 26)
    - "The Death Penalty in the United States: Imposed Law and the Role of Moral Elites". Chapter in The Imposition of Law, 1979 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 27)
    - "The Death Penalty in the United States". Chapter in Capital Punishment: Global Issues and Prospects edited by Peter Hodgkinson and Andrew Rutherford, 1996 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 28)
    - "The Death Penalty, Longhorn Style". Chapter in International Yearbook on the Death Penalty edited by William A Schabas, 1996 (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 29)
    - "The Eighth Amendment, the Death Penalty, and Human Dignity". Chapter in Human Dignity, the Bill of Rights, and Constitutional Values edited by Michael J Meyer and William A. Parent, Undated (Box 3 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 30)
    - "Execution of the Innocent". by Michael Radelet and Hugo Bedau. Chapter in America's Experiment with Capital Punishment Edited by James Acker, Undated (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 1)
    - "Fallibility and Finality: Type II Errors and Capital Punishment". Chapter in Adjudicating Death: Moral and Legal Perspectives on Capital Punishment, 1987 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 2)
    - "The Gravest Errors in Capital Cases: Convicting the Innocent". Chapter in Festschrift for Jan Stepan, Swiss Institute of Comparative Law, 1994 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 3)
    - "How to Argue About the Death Penalty". Chapter in Facing the Death Penalty: Essays on a Cruel and Unusual Punishment edited by Michael Radelet, 1989 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 4)
    - "How to Argue About the Death Penalty". Chapter in Morality in Criminal Justice, 1993 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 5)
    - "The Present Situation of the Death Penalty in the United States". Chapter in the Death Penalty, 2nd Edition, 2002 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 6)
    - "Reflections on Psychiatry and the Death Penalty". Chapter in the Mosaic of Contemporary Psychiatry in Perspective Festschrift for Louis Jolyon West, 1992 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 7)
  - Book Forwards/Postscripts, 1976-1986; 1.6
    This subseries contains drafts of forwards and postscripts that Bedau wrote for colleagues' books.
    - Forward of Death Penalty for Juveniles? By Victor L. Streib, 1986 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 8)
    - Forward of Life in the Balance Procedural Safeguards in Capital Cases by Welsh S. White, 1984 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 9)
    - Postscript of Voices Against Death edited by Philip English Mackey, 1976 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 10)
  - Testimony, 1958-1986; 1.7
    This subseries contains transcripts of expert testimonies on Capital Punishment that Bedau gave to various federal and state lawmakers.
    - California Legislature -- Assembly Criminal Justice Committee, 1973 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 11)
    - U.S. House Judiciary Committee, 1972 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 12)
    - U.S. House Judiciary Committee, 1978 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 13)
    - U.S. House Judiciary Committee, 1982 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 14)
    - U.S. House Judiciary Committee, 1986 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 15)
    - U.S. Senate Judiciary Committee, 1981 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 16)
    - New Jersey Assembly Judiciary Committee, 1958 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 17)
    - New Jersey Capital Punishment Study Commission, 1972 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 18)
    - New Jersey Legislature, 1976 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 19)
    - New York, Assembly Codes Committee, 1972 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 20)
    - Pennsylvania Testimony, 1973 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 21)
  - Reviews, 1973-1988; 1.8
    This subseries contains drafts and reprints of scholarly reviews which Bedau has written about various works on Capital Punishment.
    - "Capital Punishment: The Literature Still Says No", 1975 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 22)
    - "Challenging The Death Penalty" 1974 Harvard Civil Rights-Civil Liberties Law Review, 1973 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 23)
      Review of Cruel and Unusual: The Supreme Court and Capital Punishment by Michael Meltsner.
    - "The Future of the Death Penalty in America", 1988 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 24)
      Contemporary Psychology. Review of The Ultimate Coercive Sanction: A Cross-cultural Study of Capital Punishment by Keith Otterbein and Capital Punishment and the American Agenda by Franklin Zimring and Gordon Hawkins.
    - "Life Under Sentence of Death". Crime and Delinquency. Review of Condemned to Die by Robert Johnson, 1982 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 25)
    - "Toward a comparative Jurisprudence on Capital Punishment" Harvard Law Review, 1984 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 26)
      Review of Judicial Review of the Death Penalty by David Pannick, 1982.
    - Untitled 1980 Ethics, University of Chicago, 1979 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 27)
      Review of Capital Punishment: Crime and Morality of the Death Penalty by Walter Berns.
    - Untitled 1980 American Journal of Sociology (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 28)
      Review of The Penalty of Death by Thorsten Sellin.
  - Pamphlets, 1973-1997; 1.9
    This subseries contains drafts and reprints of the ACLU pamphlet The Case Against the Death Penalty which Bedau wrote in 1973 and has updated four times.
    - "The Case Against the Death Penalty" ACLU Pamphlet, 1973 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 29)
    - "The Case Against the Death Penalty" ACLU Pamphlet (revised 1977) (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 30)
    - "The Case Against the Death Penalty" ACLU Pamphlet (revised 1977) (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 31)
    - "The Case Against the Death Penalty" ACLU Pamphlet (revised 1984) (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 32)
    - "The Case Against the Death Penalty" ACLU Pamphlet (revised 1984) (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 33)
    - "The Case Against the Death Penalty" ACLU Pamphle (revised 1992) (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 34)
    - "The Case Against the Death Penalty" ACLU Pamphlet (revised 1997) (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 35)
  - Encyclopedia Entries, 1983-2000; 1.10
    This subseries contains drafts of articles which Bedau contributed to various encyclopedias.
    - "Capital Punishment", 1985; 1988 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 36)
    - "Capital Punishment".Encyclopedia of Crime and Justice, 1983 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 37)
    - "Capital Punishment".Encyclopedia of Crime and Justice, 1983 (Box 4 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 38)
    - "Capital Punishment", 1983 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 1)
    - "Capital Punishment", 2000 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 2)
    - "Capital Punishment", 1983 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 3)
    - "Death Penalty", 1999 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 4)
  - Interviews and Memorabilia, 1958-1987; Undated; 1.11
    This subseries contains drafts and reprints of articles about Bedau and also contains awards Bedau received, pictures and other personal memorabilia.
    - Bibliography of Bedau's works on Capital Punishment, 1958-1961 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 5)
    - Bedau Memorabilia, Undated (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 6)
    - Memorabilia -- Pictures from Annual meeting of NCADP, 1987 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 7)
    - Rough Justice -- The Death Penalty Interviews, Undated (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 8)
    - "A Trial Interview: Hugo A Bedau"Trial Magazine, by Stephen Caswell, 1974 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 9)
    - Draft of Caswell Interview, 1973 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 10)
  - Lectures, 1962-2000; 1.12
    This subseries contains lectures and addresses that Bedau gave at various classrooms, meetings, and conferences.
    - Arbitrary Death Penalty Abolition in Massachusetts" Prepared for NCADP Meeting, 2000 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 11)
    - Commission of Inquiry on the use of the Death Penalty in the United States, 1993 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 12)
    - "Constitutional Issues Raised by Capital Punishment". Bill of Rights Seminar at Harvard Law School, 1962 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 13)
    - "Crime, Capital Punishment, and Social Justice" Lecture for Symposium on Capital Punishment. Loyola University, School of Law, 1976 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 14)
    - "The Current Status of the Death Penalty" ACLU Biennial Conference, 1974 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 15)
    - "Death Penalty Exceptionalism, Texan and American" Lecture from conference on Texas and American Exceptionalism. University of Texas Law School, 2000 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 16)
    - "Moral Arguments and the Death Penalty: Is Absolute Abolition a Tenable Policy". Lecture to Annual Meeting of Eastern Division, American Philosophical Association, 1996 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 17)
    - "Moral Arguments and The Death Penalty: Is Absolute Abolition a Tenable Policy", Amherst College Conference, 1997 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 18)
    - "Public Health and the Epidemiology of the Death Penalty" Lecture. Harvard Medical School Symposium, 1982 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 19)
    - "Social Science Research in the Aftermath of Furman v. Georgia" American Society of Criminology, 1973 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 20)
    - "Some Thoughts on the Current Status of the Death Penalty in the United States" Northeastern Regional Conference of NCADP, 1986 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 21)
    - Third Annual Henry Schwarzschild Lecture, 2001 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 22)
      Bedau - Keynote Speaker.
    - Lecture Notes, 1977-1995 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 23)
    - Lecture Notes, 1977-1995 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 24)
  - Course Resource Packets, 1979-2001; 1.13
    This subseries contains various capital punishment resources that Bedau shared with his students. There are also some materials not by Bedau.
    - Capital Punishment Study Resource, 1979 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 25)
    - Capital Punishment Syllabi, 1993 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 26)
      Some Syllabi not by Bedau.
    - Centre for Capital Punishment Studies. University of Westminster, 1995-1998 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 27)
    - Centre for Capital Punishment Studies. University of Westminster, 1995-1998 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 28)
    - Philosophy 010: Death Penalty in America. Tufts University, Course Resource Packet, 1997 Spring (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 29)
    - Philosophy 010: Death Penalty in America. Tufts University, Course Resource Packet, 1998 (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 30)
    - Philosophy 010: Death Penalty in America. Tufts University, Course Resource Packet # 1, 2001 Spring (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 31)
    - Philosophy 010: Death Penalty in America. Tufts University, Course Resource Packet # 2, 2001 Spring (Box 5 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 32)
  - Conferences, 1956-2002; 1.14
    This subseries consists of materials related to various conferences which Bedau attended, but does not include any works by Bedau.
    - American Academy of Religion (Chicago), 1973 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 1)
    - American Orthopsychiatry Association, 1977 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 2)
    - Arizona State University, 1977 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 3)
    - Congress of Corrections, 1956 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 4)
    - Conference on the Death Penalty Tufts University, 1985 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 5)
    - Deterrence Conference Bowling Green, 1976-1977 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 6)
    - Florida State Conference, 1973 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 7)
    - The Future of Habeas Corpus Conference, Harvard Law School, 1993 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 8)
    - The Future of Habeas Corpus Conference, Harvard Law School, 1993 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 9)
    - The Future of Habeas Corpus Conference, Harvard Law School, 1993 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 10)
    - Interdisciplinary Conference on Capital Punishment, Georgia State University, 1980 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 11)
    - Interdisciplinary Conference on Capital Punishment, Georgia State University, 1980 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 12)
    - Interdisciplinary Conference on Capital Punishment, Georgia State University, 1980 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 13)
    - International Law and the Abolition of the Death Penalty Conference -- Galway, Ireland, 2001 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 14)
    - Jerry Gottlieb Conference Santa Barbara, 1967 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 15-17)
    - Jerry Gottlieb Conference Santa Barbara, 1967 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 16)
    - Jerry Gottlieb Conference Santa Barbara, 1967 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 17)
    - Harvard Law School Conference, 1973 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 18)
    - Harvard Law School, Wrongful Convictions Conference, 2002 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 19)
    - Howard Law School Conference, 1976 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 20)
    - Judicial Conference of the United States, 1989 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 21)
    - National Conference on Capital Punishment, 1971 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 22)
    - The Neuropsychiatric Institute at UCLA Conference, 1973 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 23)
    - SUNY Albany Conference, 1998 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 24)
    - Survey Research and the Death Penalty Conference -- Russell Sage Foundation, NYC, 1973 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 25)
    - Symposium against the Death Penalty, Thomas M. Cooley Law School, 1996 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 26)
    - University of California, 1973 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 27)
    - University of California, Irvine Conference, 2002 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 28)
    - University of Illinois, 1973 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 29)
    - University of Pennsylvania, 1973 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 30)
    - Williams College, 1972 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 31)
    - Yale Law School Conference, 1973 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 32)
    - Conferences, 1977-1989 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 23)
    - Conferences, 1983-1989 (Box 6 (1-Scholarship and Teaching), Folder 34)
- Correspondence, 1957-2003; Undated; 2; 4 cubic ft.
  - Individual, 1963-1991; Undated; 2.1
    This subseries contains correspondence organized alphabetically by name. Bedau corresponded with colleagues from other universities and colleges, researchers, students whom Bedau was mentoring or assisting, advocacy organizations, and with publishers regarding involvement with various literary projects. Correspondence includes communication with many of Bedau's colleagues including: Anthony Amsterdam, William Bowers, Peggy Davis, Watt Espy, Gerald Gottlieb, David Kendall, Douglas Lyons, Philip Mackey, Michael Radelet, Marc Riedel, Victor Streib, Neil Vidmar, Marvin Wolfgang, and Franklyn Zimring.
    - Anthony Amsterdam, 1972-1988 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 1)
    - William Bailey, 1973-1988 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 2)
    - David Baldus, 1983-1987 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 3)
    - Herbert Blumer, 1973 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 4)
    - William Bowers, 1972-1986 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 5)
    - William Bowers/Glen Pierce, 1975-1976 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 6)
    - Robert Buckout, 1974 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 7)
    - Peter Buffum, 1973 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 8)
    - David Chandler, 1973-1977 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 9)
    - Elliot Currie, 1972-1973 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 10)
    - Peggy Davis, 1973-1977 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 11)
    - Benard Diamond, 1973-1975 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 12)
    - Isaac Ehrilich, 1973-1975 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 13)
    - Phoebe Ellsworth/Lee Ross, 1973-1984 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 14)
    - Watt Espy, 1980-1985 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 15)
    - Watt Espy/ Capital Punishment Research Project, 1985-1987 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 16)
    - Tim Ford, 1973-1976 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 17)
    - Brain Forst, 1974-1977 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 18)
    - Richard Gelles/ Murray Straus, 1974-1975 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 19)
    - Gilbert Geis, 1973 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 20)
    - Jack Gibbs, 1973 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 21)
    - Jack Gibbs/Maynard Erickson, Undated (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 22)
    - Daniel Glaser, 1973-1974 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 23)
    - Arthur Goldberg Committee, 1973 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 24)
    - Gerald Gottlieb, 1967-1986 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 25)
    - Lee Hamilton, 1973-1977 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 26)
    - Richard Jacoby, 1974 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 27)
    - Ivan Jankovic, 1987-1988 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 28)
    - C.H.S. Jayewardence, 1973-1974 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 29)
    - David Kendall, 1973-1977 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 30)
    - Rupert Koeninger, 1974 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 31)
    - Lawrence Kohlberg/Donald Elfenbein, 1974-1976 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 32)
    - Solomon Korbin, 1973 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 33)
    - Alan Kringel, 1973-1974 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 34)
    - Barry Krisberg, 1972-1973 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 35)
    - Douglas Lyons, 1972-1973 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 36-37)
    - Philip Mackey, 1971-1977 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 38)
    - Philip Mackey/Research Project for MCADP, Undated (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 39)
    - James McCafferty, 1972-1973 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 40)
    - John McCloskey, 1973 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 41)